A Finding Aid to the Abraham Walkowitz Papers, 1904-1969, in the Archives of American Art AAA.walkabra
Archives of American Art
Abraham Walkowitz papers
1904-1969
AAA.walkabra
Archives of American Art
2.9 Linear feet
The papers of painter Abraham Walkowitz date from 1904-1969, and measure 2.9 linear feet. Found within the papers are biographical material; letters from artists, friends, and art collectors; business records; four interview transcripts; notes and writings; exhibition announcements, cataloges, and other printed material; and photographs of Walkowitz, friends, colleagues, and artworks.
Walkowitz, Abraham
Provenance
Portions of the papers were donated in 1959 by Abraham Walkowitz; in 1966 by Dr. Rosa E. Prigosen, the artist's niece; in 1981 through a transfer of material from the National Museum of American Art/National Portrait Gallery Library; and in 1996 by Howard and Lila Schulman.
Related Material
Also found at the Archives of American Art is an oral history interview of Abraham Walkowitz conducted by Abram Lerner and Mary Bartlett Cowdrey, December 8 and 22, 1958.
Existence and Location of Copies note
The collection was digitized in 2014 and is available via the Archives of American Art's website.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Biographical Note
Abraham Walkowitz (1878-1965) was a painter in Brooklyn, New York. Walkowitz was born in Tumen in Siberian Russia, the son of Jacob and Rita Schulman Walkowitz. Following the death of his father, a lay rabbi and cantor, in the late 1880s, Walkowitz immigrated to the United States with his mother and siblings and settled in the Lower East Side of New York City.
Walkowitz began his study of art at the Educational Alliance, at Cooper Union, and at the National Academy of Design. In early adulthood he worked as a sign painter and taught at the Educational Alliance from 1900 to 1906. He managed to save enough for passage to Paris where he continued his studies at the Académie Julian under Academic painter Jean-Paul Laurens. During this time, Walkowitz met Max Weber who introduced him to Matisse, Picasso, and Gertrude and Leo Stein. They exerted a considerable influence on Walkowitz's artistic development toward abstraction. Weber also introduced him to Isadora Duncan, whose style of improvisational dance inspired Walkowitz to create over 5,000 drawings and watercolors of her dancing form over the next four decades.
Walkowitz returned to New York in 1907 and laid claim to being the first to exhibit truly Modernist paintings in the United States with his exhibition at the Haas Gallery in 1908. After 1909, he became an intimate of Alfred Stieglitz's 291 Gallery where he became a regular exhibitor along with Arthur Dove, Marsden Hartley, and John Marin, among others. Walkowitz's work appeared in landmark avant-garde exhibitions including the 1913 Armory Show, the Forum Exhibition of 1916, the People's Art Guild showings of contemporary art from 1915-1917, and the inaugural show of the Société Anonyme in 1920.
When interest in the Modernist movement diminished during the 1930s, Walkowitz's career also diminished, but he continued as an avid member and officer in the Society of Independent Artists. In the mid-1940s, he explored the varieties of the modernist vision in the form of an exhibition of 100 portraits of Walkowitz by 100 artist colleagues. The result was widely discussed and was featured in Life magazine in 1944. In 1945, Walkowitz travelled to Kansas to reunite with his colleague, E. Haldeman-Julius, to publish in a series of books concerning Walkowitz's art work. He also executed a series of drawings of the barns and strip mines in the area. But by 1946, glaucoma had begun to impair Walkowitz's vision, leading to his eventual blindness. Also in the mid-1940s, Walkowitz lost the contents of his studio to fire.
In 1963, Walkowitz received the Marjory Peabody Award of the National Institute of Arts and Letters. His work is represented in the collections of the Newark Museum, the Whitney Museum of American Art, and the Museum of Fine Arts, Boston.
Abraham Walkowitz died on January 26, 1965 in Brooklyn, New York.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of painter Abraham Walkowitz date from 1904-1969, and measure 2.9 linear feet. Found within the papers are biographical material; letters from artists, friends, and art collectors; business records; four interview transcripts; notes and writings; exhibition announcements, catalogs, and other printed material; and photographs of Walkowitz, friends, colleagues, and artworks.
Biographical material consists of autobiographical notes, a citizenship certificate, membership and registration cards, medical records, and address books.
Letters, with scattered responses from Walkowitz, are primarily from colleagues including artists John Taylor Arms, George Biddle, Paula Eliasoph, Ivan G. Olinsky, Walter Pach, Alfred Stieglitz, Carl Van Vechten, and Max Weber, Boston art collector Louis Schapiro, publisher E. Haldeman-Julius, writer Horace Traubel, and dancers Elizabeth Duncan and Maria-Theresa Duncan, the sister and adopted daughter of Isadora Duncan respectively. Individual letters are primarily from the diverse group of notable people to whom Walkowitz had sent copies of his books. Also found are letters from art organizations and museums.
Business records consist of documents concerning the will of art collector George M. Dunaif, letters of acknowledgement of gifts of art work donated by Walkowitz to various museums, and miscellaneous financial material. Transcripts are of three interviews with Walkowitz and an interview with Walkowitz and Frank Kleinholz. Notes and writings include lists of names, addresses, and art work, miscellaneous lecture notes, and writings by Walkowitz and by others. Printed material consists of clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, reproductions of art work, and books by Walkowitz, and by Walkowitz and E. Haldeman-Julius.
The photographs series contains the most significant material in the collection. The majority of photographs are of Abraham Walkowitz, taken by many notable photographers including Arnold Genthe, Lotte Jacobi, Arnold Newman, Alfredo Valente, Carl Van Vechten, and Clarence White. Also found are photographs of friends and colleagues, as well as photographs of art work by Walkowitz and others.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 7 series:
Series 1: Biographical Material 1906-1944 (Box 1, 5; 8 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1906-1966 (Box 1; 0.8 linear feet)
Series 3: Business Records, 1930-1956 (Box 1; 5 folders)
Series 4: Interview Transcripts, 1944-1958 (Box 1; 5 folders)
Series 5: Notes and Writings, 1904-1949 (Box 1-2; 26 folders)
Series 6: Printed Material, 1910-1969 (Box 2, 5; 0.8 linear feet)
Series 7: Photographs, 1904-1958 (Box 2-5; 0.9 linear feet)
Arms, John Taylor, 1887-1953; Biddle, George, 1885-1973; Dunaif, George M.; Duncan, Elizabeth, 1871-1948; Eliasoph, Paula; Genthe, Arnold, 1869-1942; Haldeman-Julius, E. (Emanuel), 1888-1951; Jacobi, Lotte, 1896-; Kleinholz, Frank, 1901-; Maria-Theresa, 1896-1987; Newman, Arnold, 1918-2006; Olinsky, Ivan G. (Ivan Gregorewitch), 1878-1962; Pach, Walter, 1883-1958; Schapiro, Louis; Stieglitz, Alfred, 1864-1946; Traubel, Horace, 1858-1919; Valente, Alfredo; Van Vechten, Carl, 1880-1964; Weber, Max, 1881-1961; White, Clarence H., 1871-1925; Art--Collectors and collecting; Interviews; Painters--New York (State)--New York; Painting, American; Photographs; Transcripts
- Biographical Material, 1906-1944; Series 1; 8 Folders Box 1, 5
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical material consisting of scattered autobiographical notes, a citizenship certificate displaying passport stamps from 1914 and 1931, a photo admission card for museums in Rome, military registration cards, exhibition registration cards, a quarterly union membership card, two medical laboratory reports, and address books.
  Existence and Location of Copies note
  This series has been scanned in its entirety.
  - Autobiographical Notes, circa 1944 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Certificate of Citizenship, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Oversized material housed in Box 5
  - Admission Card for Museums in Rome; Military Registration Cards, 1914-1917 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Gloucester Society of Artists Membership Card; Quarterly Union Membership Card, 1926-1928 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition Registration Cards, circa 1914-1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Medical Laboratory Reports, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Address Books, circa 1906-1944 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Oversized Certificate, Scanned with Box 1, F2, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1906-1966; Series 2; 0.8 Linear feet Box 1
  Letters, with scattered responses from Walkowitz, are primarily from colleagues including artists John Taylor Arms, George Biddle, Paula Eliasoph, Ivan G. Olinsky, Walter Pach, Alfred Stieglitz, Carl Van Vechten, and Max Weber, Boston art collector Louis Schapiro, publisher E. Haldeman-Julius, writer Horace Traubel, and dancers Elizabeth Duncan and Maria-Theresa Duncan, the sister and adopted daughter of Isadora Duncan respectively.
  Individual letters are primarily from the diverse group of notable people to whom Walkowitz had sent copies of his books. Correspondents include artists George C. Ault, Oscar Bluemner, Henry Botkin, Katharine S. Dreier, Philip Evergood, Karl Knaths, Louis Lozowick, Kenneth Hayes Miller, Jules Pascin, George Rickey, and Eugene Speicher, art collectors A. C. Barnes and Duncan Phillips, Supreme Court Justice Louis D. Brandeis, philosopher John Dewey, photography pioneer George Eastman, singer Nelson Eddy, Sigmund Freud, Sidney Janis, violinist Louis Kaufman, Meyer Schapiro, writer Richard Wright, and French actress Lottie Yorska. A letter of apology from John Sloan, dated 1919, throws light on the hostility Walkowitz felt towards Sloan. Also found are letters from art organizations and museums.
  - A, 1935-1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Addison Gallery of American Art
    All-Americal Jewish Cultural Alliance (YKUF)
    American Artists Congress
    American Society of Painters, Sculptors and Gravers
    Arms, John Taylor
    Artists League of America
    Avery, Milton
  - B, 1929-1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Bezalel National Museum
    Biddle, George
    Bittel, Lt. Lester Ro.
    Brandeis, Louis D.
    Bressler, Sophie and Judson
    Brooklyn Museum
  - C, 1926-1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Coe College
    Congress for Jewish Culture Art Center
    Constant, George
    Converse, Lily S.
    Cooper Union for the Advancement of Science and Art
  - D, 1927-1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Dickinson, Sidney E.
    Duncan, Elizabeth
    Duncan, Margherita S.
    Duncan, Maria-Theresa
  - E, 1929-1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Egner, Arthur
    Eliasoph, Paula
    Evanti, Lillian
    Evergood, Philip
  - F, 1929-1956 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Ford Foundation
    Foy, Hans
    Friedlander, Isaac
  - G, 1928-1963 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Gallatin, Albert
    Gauthier, Eva
    Genauer, Emily
    Guggenheim Memorial Foundation
  - H, 1912-1959 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Haldeman-Julius, Emanuel and Sue
    Hollander, George and Bea Sterling
  - I, 1939-1953 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Isaacs, Stanley and Ethel
  - J, 1920-1964 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Janis, Sidney
    Jewish Telegraph Agency
  - K, 1929-1957 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Kellner, Gus and Mary
    Knaths, Karl
    Kraushaar, C.W.
  - L, 1907-1958 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Lane, Charles J.
    Library of Congress
    Lorber, Dr. Herman (Harry)
    Lorber, Samuel and Martha
    Lozowick, Louis
    Lutz, Mark
  - M, 1906-1966 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Mandel, A.
    Menters, Anita "Angna"
    Metropolitan Museum of Art
    Morgan LIbrary
    Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute
    Museum of Fine Arts, Boston
    Museum of Modern Art
  - N, 1931-1962 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Newark Museum
    New York Times
  - O, 1907-1949 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Olinsky, Ivan Gregorewitch
    Oppenheimer, Beatruce Biano (Opp)
  - P, 1929-1955 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Pach, Walter and Magda
    Pascin, Jules
    Pickwick Pharmacy Art School
    Prigosen, Rosa and Jacob
    Princeton Print Club
  - Q, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Quitzow, Charles A.
  - R, 1929-1962 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Roback, A.A.
    Rockefeller, John D. (Secretary)
    Rosenblum, Harry
  - Sa-Se, 1925-1958 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    San Francisco Museum of Art
    Schapiro, Louis
    Schoenfeld, Abe and Annie
    Schulman, Eileen
  - Sh-Sw, 1914-1949 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Shaskan, Alexander T.
    Smith, ALice H. J.
    Society for Independent Artists, Inc.
    Stieglitz, Alfred
  - T, 1917-1959 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Tisch, William
    Traubel, Horace
  - U, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - V, 1937-1949 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Van Arsdale, S.F.
    Van Vechten, Carl
  - W, 1922-1964 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Watson, Forbes
    Weber, Max
    Whitney Museum of American Art
    Who's Who in America
  - Y, 1929-1944 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Z, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Zirinsky, Julius
  - First Names Only and Illegible, circa 1910-circa 1960 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Drafts, cica 1930-circa 1940 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Business Records, 1930-1956; Series 3; 5 Folders Box 1
  Business records consist of documents concerning the petition by Jonas Ellis to prove the will of art collector George M. Dunaif, letters of acknowledgement of gifts of art work donated by Walkowitz to various museums and libraries including the Albright Art Gallery in Buffalo, the Museum of the City of New York, the New York Public Library, the Museum of Modern Art, and the Philadelphia Museum of Art, and miscellaneous financial material including price lists for art work and receipts.
  - Documents Concerning Petition by Jonas Ellis to Prove the Last Will and Testament of George M. Dunaif, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Acknowledgements of Gifts of Art Works from Walkowitz, 1935-1954 (Box 1, Folder 37-38)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Material, circa 1930-1956 (Box 1, Folder 39-40)
- Interview Transcripts, 1944-1958; Series 4; 5 Folders Box 1
  Transcripts are of three interviews with Walkowitz and an interview with Walkowitz and Frank Kleinholz.
  - Transcript of Radio Station WNYC Interview with Walkowitz and Frank Kleinholz, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Draft Transcript of First Interview with Walkowitz, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Draft Transcript of Second Interview with Walkowitz, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Draft Transcript of Interview with Walkowitz, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 44-45)
- Notes and Writings, 1904-1949; Series 5; 0.3 Linear feet Box 1-2
  Notes and writings include lists of names, addresses, and art work, miscellaneous lecture notes, and writings by Walkowitz about art, exhibitions, Isadora Duncan, and Alfred Stieglitz. Writings by others include typescripts about Walkowitz by Sidney Janis, Walter Pach, Carl Van Vechten, and John Weichsel, writings about Isadora Duncan are by her adopted daughter, Maria Theresa Duncan, and Mary Fanton Roberts.
  - Lists of Names, circa 1904-1949 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Address Lists, circa 1904-1949 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Lists of Art Work, circa 1904-1949 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Lecture Notes, circa 1904-1949 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Notes, circa 1904-1949 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Manuscript by Walkowitz for "A Portrait,", circa 1904-1949 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Typescript by Walkowitz for "A Portrait of Stieglitz,", circa 1904-1949 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Writings by Walkowitz on Art, circa 1904-1932 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Manuscript by Walkowitz for "To the call of Peace,", 1904 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Typescript for Guggenheim Fellowship, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Writings by Walkowitz on Isadora Duncan, circa 1931 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Writings by Walkowitz Concerning the Brooklyn Museum Exhibition One Hundred Artists and Walkowitz, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Writings by Walkowitz on "The Artist,", 1944 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Manuscript by Walkowitz "Remembering Isadora,", 1944 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Writings by Others in Hebrew, circa 1904-1949 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Typescripts about Walkowitz by Sidney Janis, John Weichsel, and Others, circa 1904-1949 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript "Isadora (The Artist), Daughter of Prometheus" by Maria Theresa Duncan, circa 1904-1949 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
  - Manuscript "Reverence for Life" by Miss Clifford Williams; Typescript "Walkowitz and Tradition" by Walter Pach, 1913-1925 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Autobiographical Typescript by Mandel, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Typescript "Remembering Isadora" by Mary Fanton Roberts, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Typescript about Walkowitz's Work Demonstration by James Johnson Sweeney, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Writings Concerning Exhibition of Walkowitz's Drawings of Isadora Duncan by Maria Theresa Duncan, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Typescripts about Walkowitz by David Diamondstein, Benjamin Kopman, and Jerome Mellquist, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Typescript Concerning Exhibition of Walkowitz's Drawings of Isadora Duncan by an Unidentified Author, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Typescripts about Walkowitz by A. L. Chanin, David Ignatoff, Bernard Myers, Amedee J. Ozenfant, and Carl Van Vechten, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Printed Material, 1910-1969; Series 6; 0.8 Linear feet Box 2, 5
  Printed material consists of clippings and periodicals, exhibition announcements and catalogs for Walkowitz, catalogs of art work in the Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, and the Whitney Museum of American Art, reproductions of art work, a brochure for Walkowitz's book 100 Drawings, and books. Miscellaneous printed material includes a reproduction of a group photograph of artists Maurice Braun, Gaston Busch, William Oberhardt, Ivan Olinsky, Ernest David Roth, Frederick Starr, Maurice Sterne, Edgar Ward, Samuel Weis, and Lee Woodward Zeigler. There is also a bookplate for Louis Schapiro designed by Walkowitz. Clippings concern Walkowitz, his friends and colleagues, and art in general. When possible, the names of full publications have been provided at the folder level.
  This series has been partially scanned. In some cases, only relevant pages of printed materials have been scanned.
  - Undated Clippings, circa 1910-1969 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Clippings and Periodicals, 1910-1912 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Clippings and Periodicals, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Camera Work, Volume XLIV
  - Clippings and Periodicals, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Current Opinion
  - Clippings and Periodicals, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
    Pagan, July-August and The Masses, November-December
  - Clippings and Periodicals, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Clippings and Periodicals, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    The New Renaissance
  - Clippings and Periodicals, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    The Future, May
  - Clippings and Periodicals, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Clippings and Periodicals, 1942-1944 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Clippings and Periodicals, 1947-1949 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Clippings and Periodicals, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Clippings and Periodicals, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Clippings and Periodicals, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Yiddishe Kultur and Arts Digest, October
  - Clippings and Periodicals, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Art News, March
  - Clippings and Periodicals, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    The Brooklyn Jewish Center Review
  - Clippings and Periodicals, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Clippings and Periodicals, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 31-32)
    Arts and Art News
  - Clippings and Periodicals, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Clippings and Periodicals, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    Arts, March
  - Clippings and Periodicals, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Clippings and Periodicals, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 36-38)
  - Clippings and Periodicals, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, circa 1916-1966 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1928-1929 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1930-1937 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    Oversized material housed in Box 5, F1
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1947-1949 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1952-1959 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Catalog of Works in the Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Catalogs of the Collection of the Whitney Museum of American Art, 1952-1960 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Reproductions of Art Work, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Brochure for 100 Drawings by Abraham Walkowitz, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - 100 Drawings by Abraham Walkowitz, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - 100 Paintings and Drawings from the Objective to Abstract by Abraham Walkowitz, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Isadora Duncan in Her Dances by Abraham Walkowitz, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Ghetto Motifs by Abraham Walkowitz, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Barns and Coal Mines Around Girard, Kansas by Abraham Walkowitz and E. Haldeman-Julius, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Improvisations of New York: A Symphony in Lines by Abraham Walkowitz, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Art from Life to Life by Abraham Walkowitz, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1910-1969 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Oversized Exhibition Announcement, Scanned with Box 2, F44, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Photographs, 1904-1958; Series 7; 0.9 Linear feet Box 2-5
  The majority of photographs are of Abraham Walkowitz, taken by miscellaneous photographers including Arnold Genthe, Lotte Jacobi, Sacha Kolin, George Lohr, Arnold Newman, Yolla Niclas, Ruth Orkin, Roy Schatt, Marcia Stein, Harry Teichlauf, Alfredo Valente, Carl Van Vechten, Clarence White, and George Wiesner. Two important photographs show Walkowitz on a picnic with his friends, Agnes Ernst (Mrs. Eugene Meyer), Paul Haviland, J. B. Kerfoot, John Marin, Katharine N. Rhoades, and Alfred Stieglitz and his wife. Photographs of friends and colleagues are also of Walkowitz with Fred Gardner, Joseph Pollet, and John Sloan at a Society of Independent Artists exhibition. There are also photographs of Henry Botkin, Stefano Cusumano, Raphael Soyer, and Alfredo Valente. Photographs are also of art work by Walkowitz and others.
  This series has been partially scanned. Duplicates have not been scanned.
  - Portraits, Abraham Walkowitz, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Portraits, Abraham Walkowitz, circa 1920 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Portraits, Abraham Walkowitz, circa 1930 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Portraits, Abraham Walkowitz, circa 1937 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Portraits, Abraham Walkowitz, circa 1940 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Portraits, Abraham Walkowitz with Art, circa 1940 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Portraits, Abraham Walkowitz with Art, circa 1950 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Portraits, Abraham Walkowitz, circa 1950 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Portraits, Abraham Walkowitz, circa 1950 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Portraits, Abraham Walkowitz, circa 1950 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Portraits, Abraham Walkowitz with Art, circa 1950 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Portraits, Abraham Walkowitz, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    Oversized material housed in Box 5, F2
  - Portraits of Abraham Walkowitz, by Arnold Genthe, 1911-1913 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Portraits of Abraham Walkowitz, by Arnold Genthe, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Portraits of Abraham Walkowitz, by Arnold Genthe, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
  - Portraits of Abraham Walkowitz, by Arnold Genthe, 1920 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Portraits of Abraham Walkowitz, by Arnold Genthe, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
  - Photographs of Abraham Walkowitz by Lotte Jacobi, circa 1950 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Photographs of Abraham Walkowitz and Henry Botkin by Sacha Kolin, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 3, Folder 9-14)